(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
はららはらり　今　踊り踊れ
Halarahalarai, now dance, dance
恋焦がれ遊べ　桜打て歌え
Play with yearning, strike the cherry blossoms and sing
花に舞い散れ　今　戻り戻せ
Scatter like flowers, now return, return
酔狂に遊べさぁ　此処で踊れ
Play in madness, come, dance here
さぁ此処で踊れ！
Come, dance here!
ひゆるりらぼっぱ
Lyrics, Music: ruki
Hyururira Boppa
日進月歩　八百万時が過ぎゆく
Day by day, eight million moments pass by
色取り取り様々連林囃子
Many colors, various forest rhythms
あんな事も　籠掘り込み
Throwing even those things into the basket
欲にまみれ生きていたい
I want to live covered in desires
人生寄り道　回り道
Life is a detour, a roundabout way
生きたいように生きなはれや
Live exactly as you want to
はららはらり　今　踊り踊れ
Halarahalarai, now dance, dance
恋焦がれ遊べ　桜打て歌え
Play with yearning, strike the cherry blossoms and sing
花に舞い散れ　今　戻り戻せ
Scatter like flowers, now return, return
酔狂に遊べさぁ　此処で踊れ
Play in madness, come, dance here
ひゆるりら　ひゆるりらぼっぱ
Hyururira, Hyururira-boppa
喜怒哀楽　八百万時が過ぎ去る
The four emotions; eight million moments pass away
酸いも甘いも祭り囃子
Both sour and sweet, the festival music
味わい尽くしてしまいましょう
Let's savor it all to the end
さぁ何から平らげよう
Now, what shall we devour first?
人生気づけば　夢の如し
Before you know it, life is like a dream
命の花を打ち上げましょう
Let's set off the flowers of our lives
はららはらり　今　踊り踊れ
Halarahalarai, now dance, dance
恋焦がれ遊べ　桜打て歌え
Play with yearning, strike the cherry blossoms and sing
花に舞い散れ　今　戻り戻せ
Scatter like flowers, now return, return
酔狂に遊べさぁ　此処で踊れ
Play in madness, come, dance here
ひゆるりら　ひゆるりらぼっぱ
Hyururira, Hyururira-boppa
花よ花よ　誇りなさい
Flower, O flower, be proud
真直ぐな心なき君のまま
Just as you are, without a single honest care
上を向いてご覧なさい
Look up and see
最期の日まで花であれ
Be a flower until your final day
はららはらり　今　踊り踊れ
Halarahalarai, now dance, dance
恋焦がれ遊べ　桜打て歌え
Play with yearning, strike the cherry blossoms and sing
花に舞い散れ　今　戻り戻せ
Scatter like flowers, now return, return
酔狂に遊べさぁ　此処で踊れ
Play in madness, come, dance here
はららはらり　今　踊り踊れ...
Halarahalarai, now dance, dance...
遊べさあ
Come on, let's play
喰らって唄え
Eat it up and sing
離れ離れでも花火上げて
Even if we're apart, let's set off fireworks
酔狂に遊べさあ
Come on, play with eccentricity
ここで踊れ
Dance right here
ひるひるりらら ひるりらぱっぱ
Hiru-hirurirara, hirurira-pappa
ねえ
Hey
あんたがっちゃいねえ
You're so tacky
誰そう願えど手元の世界に夢中
No matter who wishes so, I'm obsessed with the world in my hands
化け物の飼い方を学んでる
I'm learning how to keep a monster
選ばれるためなら舌を売る
I'll sell my tongue just to be chosen
裏切られた分だけ墓を掘る
I'll dig as many graves as I've been betrayed
ヘラヘラの御紬どうにかして
Do something about that frivolous weaving
うすうす寒い言葉ばかり丸
Just a bunch of faintly chilling words
覚えない言葉バイバイできるなら
If I can say goodbye to words I don't remember
阿修羅にだってなれるわ
I can even become an Ashura
逃げるエスケープ・エスケープ端から端のまま
Running, escape, escape, staying from end to end
飛べるステップ・ステップ汚名のまま
Flying, step, step, staying with the infamy
アンダスタン？
Understand?
どどど、ドレンマ真様食らって
Eat up the d-d-d-dilemma, just like that
語るスニーク・スニーク阿修羅の中
Talking, sneak, sneak, inside the Ashura
跳ねるスキップ・スキップ遊べのかぱ
Jumping, skip, skip, let's play
アンダスタン？
Understand?
いっそ骨の髄までしゃぶって
Might as well suck it to the marrow
ねえ、あんたがっちゃいねえ
Hey, you're so tacky
日々の染みを木々にくべて暖を取り合う
Feeding daily stains to the trees, we warm each other
義を強いて枯れの獅子はちりぢりになる
Forcing righteousness, the withered lions scatter
知りもせずに意味を美意識だと崇める
Worshipping meaning as aesthetics without even knowing
疑似餌地道死の己が性
Lure, steady, death, my own nature
不快な語彙宅の古媚に
In the old flattery of unpleasant vocabulary
上辺の面をして可愛がった
Wore a superficial face and showed affection
下らない忖度踊るくらいなら
If I have to dance to worthless conjectures
悪魔と手繋ぐわ
I'll hold hands with the devil
逃げるエスケープ・エスケープ端から端のまま
Running, escape, escape, staying from end to end
飛べるステップ・ステップ汚名のまま
Flying, step, step, staying with the infamy
アンダスタン？
Understand?
浴び地獄の果てまでロッカー
Bathe in it, a rocker until the end of hell
語るスニーク・スニーク阿修羅の中
Talking, sneak, sneak, inside the Ashura
跳ねるスキップ・スキップ遊べのかぱ
Jumping, skip, skip, let's play
アンダスタン？
Understand?
赤の他人の世であの世で行って
In this world of total strangers, go to the other world
逃げるエスケープ・エスケープ端から端のまま
Running, escape, escape, staying from end to end
飛べるステップ・ステップ汚名のまま
Flying, step, step, staying with the infamy
アンダスタン？
Understand?
どどど、ドレンマ真様食らって
Eat up the d-d-d-dilemma, just like that
語るスニーク・スニーク阿修羅の中
Talking, sneak, sneak, inside the Ashura
跳ねるスキップ・スキップ遊べのかぱ
Jumping, skip, skip, let's play
アンダスタン？
Understand?
ねえ、ぎゃあぎゃあ言っちゃって
Hey, keep on screaming
はぁ？
Huh?
頭を垂れれねえ
I can't bow my head
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo!
What's up! I am Chaos, the End of Ends,
a steward's trap in a cage of ice, your best friend,
Hakos Baelz from Hololive English!
我はカオス、我の果てザ・エンド、
I am Chaos, the End of Ends,
氷の檻に封印されし鉄鼠のハコス、
Hakos the Iron Rat, sealed in a cage of ice,
汝の友、ホロライブEnglishのハコス・ベールズです！
your best friend, Hakos Baelz from Hololive English!
Witness me!
Guys, I'm going to die.
Welcome to KAGURA: Dance with the Gods,
my not-really-birthday-not-birthday-birthday Live 2025!
誕生日じゃない生誕ライブにようこそ！
Welcome to my not-a-birthday birthday live!
We opened with two songs. We already did two songs.
I hope you enjoyed it. もう2曲やってたんでね！
I hope you enjoyed it. We've already done two songs!
もう...
Already...
汐を... 汐を見たんです。今はね。
The salt... I was looking at the salt. For now.
Ne! Ah, I wanted to do like... I just wanted to say hi to you guys as well.
Right! Ah, I wanted to do like... I just wanted to say hi to you guys as well.
This is like the first time I get to say hi to you guys as well.
Look at the stage!
このステージ見て！ ウッホー！
Look at this stage! Woohoo!
This is my... this is my Japanese heart stage. 見て！ This is also a Taiko here.
This is my... this is my Japanese heart stage. Look! This is also a Taiko here.
Don don don!
That's not how you play Taiko. Oh my goodness. Anyway...
This is the stage that I... that was specially created for this live.
Because... the theme of today's live, I don't know if you've noticed, is...
...the aesthetics of traditional Japanese...
No, that's not how it goes. It's the traditional Japanese aesthetic plus dance.
えっとね、今日のライブね、テーマはね、和とダンスですよ。
Well, for today's live, the theme is 'Wa' and dance.
なんかね... So a lot of the songs tonight may have kind of that traditional feel.
Somehow... So a lot of the songs tonight may have kind of that traditional feel.
えっと、今夜の曲はね、ちょっと「和」が入ってるかな？っていう気持ちで、あの...
Well, tonight's songs... with a feeling that they have a bit of 'Wa' in them, um...
パフォーマンスしたいなと思ってます。
...I'm thinking I'd like to perform.
So, um, get excited! There's still a lot more to come.
Please use the hashtag as well. Uh... dotchi? This one!
Please use the hashtag as well. Uh... which one? This one!
Please use the hashtag #BaeDDay2025.
Who knows? I might be gone by the end. Who knows? I really don't know if I'm gonna survive tonight.
But, I hope you are in the ride... Oh, that's not how the saying goes. Wow, I actually can't talk.
Hope you guys stay on this crazy ride with me until the very end.
Um, but yeah! So we did Kyutyu-ri-pappa... I can never say that song right.
As the opening, it was so much fun.
De-de-de-de-de-de-de-de-de-de-de with my amazing dancers, as usual.
I hope that was a good opener. And also, Ashi-no-chon!
For those who watched the afternoon dance... dance bit, I hope...
...if you haven't, please check it out.
あの、午後にね、ダンスリハの部分もね、見てない方はぜひ見ててください。
Um, if you haven't seen the dance rehearsal part in the afternoon, please do check it out.
I learned the last chorus today at noon, so please watch it.
I did my best. So, I hope Miki-sensei is proud of me. Yes!
Uh, that's... and you can compare how I was at, you know, the afternoon with what you just saw.
But! The show is going to keep on going, it keeps on giving.
So, it is time for the very first guest.
ゲスト、ゲストパート入りますんですけど、誰かな？
Guest, we're moving on to the guest part, but I wonder who it is?
Who could it be? I don't know, we'll see.
You better stay, okay? I'm gonna go. Don't... don't you go anywhere. Okay?
雷鳴！
Thunderclap!
心ゆくまで雷鳴
Thunderclap to your heart's content
どちらか天井全景
A panoramic view of the ceiling
悪魔の再現
A reproduction of the devil
熾るは東京旋回
Kindling, a Tokyo revolution
界雷
Lyrics, Music: yowanecity
Kairai
熾るは東京旋回
Kindling, a Tokyo revolution
焦がれ浴びたい 情熱繚乱
Longing to bask in a profusion of passion
狂うた動乱のまにまに
In the midst of a mad upheaval
言葉も無いやと呟いた
I muttered that there are no words
ヘルタースケルター心臓に
Helter-skelter, in my heart
構えろよジーザス 祈ったって恩寵
Ready yourself, Jesus; even a prayer is a blessing
崩壊するドメスティックブランド
A collapsing domestic brand
雑多風上 鳴動せよ
In the miscellaneous windward, let it rumble
覚醒する闘志と
With an awakening fighting spirit
稲光り奔る影
And a shadow racing through lightning
乾杯 禅 尽きぬ闇風
Cheers, Zen, to the endless dark wind
誰彼の塩梅 モードウェザー
The state of whoever, mode weather
喰らえ 止まらぬ 狂った手も
Take this, even these mad, unstoppable hands
燃える光に
Into the burning light
宿りし神の 綴じ目の限りを
To the limit of the seams of the indwelling god
雷鳴！
Thunderclap!
共鳴 愛した僕の震を
Resonance, the tremor of my love
愚弄になって 飛び出せ心臓
Turn into mockery, burst forth, my heart
想像すれば全部
If you imagine it, everything
最悪も魔の色は
Even the worst, the color of the devil
目指して揺らして
Aiming and swaying
超えたいのになあと
Thinking how I want to overcome it
頭 鳴らして 雷鳴
Ringing in my head, a thunderclap
起きよの果て 雷鳴
The end of awakening, a thunderclap
闇下り 天上全景
Descending into darkness, a panoramic view of the ceiling
改悛の声明を
A declaration of penitence
響かせ 東京旋回
Make it resound, a Tokyo revolution
今宵 奔放な 狂うた動乱
Tonight, a wild and mad upheaval
擦るは諸悪の何彼に
Rubbing against whatever of all evils
旋回 万象 万華鏡
Rotation, all of nature, a kaleidoscope
悶えた ヘルタースケルター 心臓に
Writhing helter-skelter, in my heart
動じない 試されてみたい
Unperturbed, I want to be tested
コンクリートジャングル
Concrete jungle
一夜一夜で 終わらぬ大道
Night after night, the endless main road
酔いしれろ 今宵は 東京旋回
Get intoxicated; tonight is a Tokyo revolution
中枢的 都市の
Of the pivotal city
私 あの ブルジョワ
I am that bourgeois
改良 全部 不当
Improvements are all unfair
加速す 逆戻のウェザー
Accelerating, a backward-turning weather
喰らいつく 胸に
Biting into my chest
葛藤が覆うと
When conflict covers it
灯し
Light it up
照らせよ 若夜
Illuminate the young night
綴じ目の 限りを
To the limit of the seams
僕の世話
My care
傀儡になって飛び出すんぞ
Becoming a puppet and jumping out
想像すれば全部採択
If you imagine it, it's all adopted
雲間の威風は
The majesty between the clouds
躍動して揺らして
Pulsating and shaking
肥えた祈りの果てへと
To the end of a fertile prayer
空しく虚勢
Vain bluster
内面喪失終了
Loss of inner self complete
ぎこちなくも晴れ渡る様子
Appearing to clear up, even if awkwardly
全て吹き飛ばせ
Blow it all away
雲も魔も厄も
The clouds, the demons, and the misfortune
躍動して揺らして
Pulsating and shaking
肥えた祈りの果てへと
To the end of a fertile prayer
響け雷鳴
Resonate, thunderclaps!
わああ！ KANKANさん来た！！
Waaaa! KANKAN is here!!
...すごい激... (笑) 自己紹介お願いしていいですか？
...Such intensity... (laughs) Could you please introduce yourself?
はい。えーと、歌い手として、そしてオリジナル曲も出したりしてる、えーと、歌い手のKANKANと申します。
Yes. Um, as an utaite, and someone who releases original songs as well, um, I am KANKAN.
よろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to my work.
わああ！本当に来てくれてありがとうございます！
Waaaa! Thank you so much for coming!
もちろん、もちろん。ありがとうございます。
Of course, of course. Thank you.
ありがとうございます... もう、このままに... このままで話そう... 本当に...
Thank you... Oh, just like this... let's talk like this... Really...
立ち... 立ちましょうか？ 本当にすみません。失礼しました。
Stand... Shall we stand up? I'm so sorry. Pardon me.
本当にね、元々KANKANさんの大ファンなんで、本当に。
Really, I've been a huge fan of KANKAN from the start, truly.
ありがとうございます。光栄です。ありがとうございます。
Thank you. I'm honored. Thank you.
あの、ちょっとまあ、お恥ずかしい話なんですけど...
Um, this is a bit of an embarrassing story, but...
あの、KANKANさんの曲を初めて聞いた時、電車中にたまたまに流れたんですよ。
When I first heard KANKAN's music, it happened to play while I was on the train.
で、普通に夢中になってて、あの、降りるトコも乗り過ぎました。
And I just got so absorbed in it that I missed my stop.
おお！！ そんな夢中になって聞いてくれてたんですか？
Oh!! You were listening that intently?
本当にめちゃくちゃ綺麗で... はい、本当に一緒に『傀儡』歌って、できて、本当に嬉しい！
It was just so incredibly beautiful... Yes, I'm so happy we could sing "Kaira" together!
こちらこそ本当に。素敵な機会をいただいて。
Same here, really. Thank you for this wonderful opportunity.
まさかこの『傀儡』を選択してもらえると思ってなくて。
I never thought you'd choose "Kaira."
まさかのチョイスなんですよ、自分的には。
It was a surprising choice for me, personally.
うわあ。でもね、さっきも必死で歌ったんですけども、KANKANさんの声ってさ、もうヤバイですよ、本当に。
Wow. But you know, I was singing my heart out just now, but KANKAN's voice is just... it's insane, really.
恐縮です。
You're too kind.
で、なんとKANKANさん、これも3D初登場じゃないですか！
And KANKAN, this is also your 3D debut, isn't it!
そうなんですよ。もう全部が初めてなんですよ、今日。全部初めて。全部。
That's right. Everything is a first today. Everything is a first. Everything.
うわあ！その動き見せてくださいよ、もう。うわあ！ 3D、どういう感じですか？ KANKANを見ろ！
Wow! Show us those moves! Wow! How is 3D feeling? Look at KANKAN!
どういう感じ？
How does it feel?
え、やっぱりなんか、普段はライブ出る時は、やっぱり生身の体で出ることが多いんですけど。
Well, usually when I perform live, I'm often there in the flesh.
はい。やっぱり全然動き方とかも違うし、全てが新感覚で。おお、はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes. But the way I move and everything is totally different, it's a whole new sensation. Oh, yes, thank you.
いや、素晴らしい！ 楽しいめちゃくちゃ！ 素晴らしい3D世界へようこそ！
No, it's wonderful! It's so much fun! Welcome to the wonderful world of 3D!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
で、あの... 来ました。はい。今回の『傀儡』っていう歌、一緒にあの歌ったんですけど、KANKANさんのオリ曲ですよね。
And, um... here it is. Yes. We sang "Kaira" together today, which is an original song of yours.
あ、そうです。私の、はい。柊マグネタイトさんに作っていただきました素敵な楽曲を、ぜひ。
Ah, yes. It's mine, yes. It's a wonderful track that Hiiragi Magnetite created for me.
いえ。あの、まあ歌詞がめちゃくちゃ難しいんですけど、あの...
Yeah. Um, well the lyrics are incredibly difficult, but...
そうですね。早口だし、詰まってるし、リズムが大変。はい。
That's true. It's fast-paced, packed with words, and the rhythm is tough. Yes.
です。まあちょっとあの、意味とか曲に関してちょっと聞きたいなって思ってるんですけど。
Right. Well, I'd like to ask a bit about the meaning and the song itself.
あ、もうなんか、『傀儡』っていうタイトルからしても、雷がついてるじゃないですか。はい！
Ah, well, even from the title "Kaira," it's got lightning in it, doesn't it? Yes!
もうとにかくみんなに、稲妻のような衝撃を与えたいっていう気持ちからで... ちょっとオーダーして、柊マグネタイトさんに。
Basically, from the feeling of wanting to give everyone a shock like a bolt of lightning... I requested that from Hiiragi Magnetite.
もう柊マグネタイトさんならではの、やっぱり迫力のある楽曲を作ってもらいたかったので。
I really wanted them to create a powerful track, which is their specialty.
で、その結果この素敵な楽曲を作っていただいたんです。
And as a result, they created this wonderful piece of music.
素晴らしい、本当に。今後もね、一緒になにかコラボできて、本当に... あの... あ、もうぜひ！
Wonderful, truly. In the future as well, I'd love to collaborate on something again... Ah, absolutely!
今日もう... もう言葉出ないヤバイ。どうしよう。すごい全力で歌ったから。
Today I just... I'm speechless, it's crazy. What should I do? Because you sang with all your might.
本当どうしよう、本当に。もうファンの気持ちはこういう感じなんだなって。いや、本当にそう思って嬉しいまた。
I really don't know. So this is how a fan feels. I'm just so happy once again.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
今度一緒に歌って... できたら嬉しいと思います。あ、またぜひ。お願いします。ありがとうございます。
I hope we can sing together again. Ah, definitely again. Please. Thank you.
ありがとうございます。あとみんなもね、あのKANKANさんのチャンネルとかどうぞ、もうぜひ見てみてください。あ、もうぜひぜひ。いっぱい良い曲あるんで。
Thank you. Also, everyone, please go and check out KANKAN's channel and everything. Ah, please do. There are lots of great songs.
いや本当です！ 本当、実... 本当に言わせていただきます。すべて良い曲なんで、聴いてください本当。
It's true! Honestly... I'm telling you. Every song is great, so please listen to them.
ありがとうございます。ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Thank you. Please do.
And overseas fans as well, uh, this is KANKAN.
Please check, please check the channel out. They're amazing.
もう、こと... 言葉出ないよ。ごめん... KANKANがえごく... えぐいから。
I'm speechless. Sorry... KANKAN is just too amazing.
I'm like a deer in headlights right now.
I'm such a big fan of their work, so please do check them out.
で...
And...
はい。
Yes.
あの、もう、これで終わらせたくないんだけど。
Um, I really don't want this to end here.
はい。もうね、時間があるからね。
Yeah. But you know, time's ticking.
まあね。
True.
やだ！
No way!
また今度しましょう。
Let's do this again sometime.
はい！ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Yes! I'd love that.
お願いします。本当ありがとうございました。
Please do. Thank you so much.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!
お誕生日おめでとうございます。
Happy birthday.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
皆さんありがとうございました！
Thank you everyone!
カンカンでーす。
I'm Kankan!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
I'm so sad.
But the show must continue!
ここからまだ続きあるんで、
There's more coming up, so
見ててね！
keep watching!
はい、OKです。
Alright, I'm ready.
行きます。
Here I go.
宵々古今
Lyrics: Reol Music: Giga, Reol
Yoiyoi Kokon
だっしゃいな兵なり
A common soldier with no style,
時が来た正しい
the time has come, it's right.
夢現つやなまめかしき
The lines between dreams and reality are blurred and alluring.
変わりゆくことに
Towards the changing things,
恐れなしのびけ
I have no fear, so stand back.
ならぬのは御免
Refusing to change is out of the question.
天真爛漫な
Innocent and cheerful,
君達が誘う
we invite you.
夜な夜な後ろ髪引かれて
Night after night, feelings lingering,
踏み出すべく成り
it's time to take a step.
えーい、えーい、えー
A-ay, a-ay, ay!
はい、アリストダリの
Yes, Aristotelian
浮世なら
if it's this floating world,
明日知らぬもの
those who don't know tomorrow
はたまたキメラだけだ
are just chimeras anyway.
酔いどれ踊れや 呑めや唄えや
Drunkenly dance, drink, and sing!
案ずることなどないな この世は
There's nothing to worry about in this world.
飛ぶ様は恨めし 現実ばらばら
The way things fly is bitter, reality is in pieces.
悲しがって観念 真相は
Get caught up in sadness, the truth is...
それ！それ！それ！それ！
Sore! Sore! Sore! Sore!
今を嘆いても 昔を愛でても
Whether you lament the present or cherish the past,
君の心の内の涙は乾かん
the tears in your heart will not dry.
それじゃ叶わん どこにいても
That won't do, no matter where you are.
目眩く舞台に 君を連れて
To the dazzling stage, I'll take you away.
甘み出なまがひ
Sweetness leaks out, a sham,
ひとぞ悲しき
people are so sad.
身勝手なのが
Being selfish is
世の理か
the way of the world.
万物移ろう
All things change,
虚像愛を
and virtual love.
俗なくたえなどはあらざらん
Commonplace decay will not exist.
僕ら巡り合うこと
Our paths crossing
まさに一期一会
is truly a once-in-a-lifetime encounter.
酸いも甘いも
Both the sour and the sweet,
増し増しねん
keep increasing,
吊り去ってこの手を握って
let's get carried away, hold this hand.
行きづらいここ
This hard-to-live-in
浮世から
floating world,
旗を掲げよ
raise the flag,
宵闇が明く
the dusk will dawn.
宵いどれ踊れや 呑めや回せや
Drunkenly dance, drink, and spin!
昔も今も変わらず 浮世は
Whether past or present, the floating world doesn't change.
飛ぶ様は気まぐれ いつだって散り散り
The way things fly is fickle, always scattering.
ぼかし三昧で放つ 人間で
Absorbed in blurring, released as a human...
それ！それ！それ！それ！
Sore! Sore! Sore! Sore!
どこまでも春も 凍てつく雪の日も
How far the spring goes, and even on freezing snowy days,
ひたすら待つの待つの待つ 君と見よう
I just wait and wait and wait, let's see it with you.
色とりどりの
The various colors,
どこまでも成る話を 眺めて
looking at the stories that unfold forever.
仰向けで 花いちもんめ
Lying on our backs, Hana Ichimonme.
欲しがる欲しがる欲しがる声
Voices wanting, wanting, wanting.
買って嬉しい 買って嬉しい
Happy to win, happy to win.
負けない負けない負けないじゃ 見つからない
If you don't lose, you won't find it.
はい、やった！はい、やった！
Hiyassa! Hiyassa!
未だ進む道半ばかな
Still halfway through the road ahead.
はい、やった！はい、やった！
Hiyassa! Hiyassa!
如何なる時も歩を前出せ
Always take one step forward, no matter when.
はい、アリストダリの
Yes, Aristotelian
浮世なら
if it's this floating world,
明日知らぬもの
those who don't know tomorrow
はたまたキメラだけだ
are just chimeras anyway.
酔いどれ踊れや 呑めや唄えや
Drunkenly dance, drink, and sing!
案ずることなどないな この世は
There's nothing to worry about in this world.
飛ぶ様は恨めし 現実ばらばら
The way things fly is bitter, reality is in pieces.
悲しがって観念 真相は
Get caught up in sadness, the truth is...
それ！それ！それ！それ！
Sore! Sore! Sore! Sore!
今を嘆いても 昔を愛でても
Whether you lament the present or cherish the past,
君の心の内の涙は乾かん
the tears in your heart will not dry.
それじゃ叶わん どこにいても
That won't do, no matter where you are.
目眩く舞台は 宵々君を連れて
The dazzling stage, dusk after dusk, I'll take you away.
甘み出なまがひ
Sweetness leaks out, a sham,
ひとぞ恋しき
people are so nostalgic.
身勝手なのが
Being selfish is
世の理か
the way of the world.
うつろわここ
Transient is here,
こころならずとも
even if not intentional.
おそれることなどあらざらん
There is nothing to fear.
朔の贄
Saku no Nie (The Sacrifice of the New Moon)
この命をさあ捧げる
I shall offer up this life.
運命なら抗うのは幼ない
If it's destiny, resisting it is futile.
孤児になった父母が残した
My parents, who made me an orphan, left behind...
その眼差しは心の呪いとなる
...a gaze that becomes a curse upon my heart.
憎しみが争いを 争いが悲しみを
Hatred brings conflict, and conflict brings sorrow.
輪のように世界をかき乱すなら
If it disturbs the world like a cycle...
小さなこの命に生きる意味を
...then the meaning of living in this small life...
あなたが宿したんだ
...is something you have instilled in me.
禍物同士運命の采が並べた
Evil entities arranged by the die of fate.
願わくば最後まで
If I may wish, until the very end...
この想いをこの心を
These feelings, this heart...
あなたに捧げるのならば
...if I am to offer them to you...
慰めも憐れみもいらないから
...then I need neither comfort nor pity.
この誓いをこの運命を
This vow, this destiny...
あなたが望むのならば
...if it is what you desire...
苦しみも悲しみも抱きしめるから
...then I will embrace both the pain and the sorrow.
喝采を浴びるのは人ならざる異形の
Basking in the applause are non-human monstrosities.
逆光に隠れるのは人の形潜むの
Hiding in the backlight are those dwelling in human form.
禍物同士運命の采が並べた
Evil entities arranged by the die of fate.
願わくば最後までその瞳を
If I may wish, until the very end, those eyes...
この命をこの世界を
This life, this world...
あなたが受け入れるなら
...if you accept them...
憎しみも悲しみもいらないから
...then I need neither hatred nor sorrow.
この想いをこの心を
These feelings, this heart...
あなたに捧げるのならば
...if I am to offer them to you...
その命を響かせて
...then let that life resonate.
この誓いをこの運命を
This vow, this destiny...
あなたが望むのならば
...if it is what you desire...
苦しみも悲しみも抱きしめるから
Then I will embrace both the pain and the sorrow.
抱きしめるから
Because I will embrace them.
Hey、ホントつまらねぇと言ってやるよこの場で
Hey, I'll tell you right here, it's really boring.
あたりさわりなくして恥さえも回答爆など
Smoothing things over, even shame is like a feedback loop.
そうずっと変わらないでずっと変わり続ける
Yes, staying the same forever, and changing forever.
五里霧中に媚びずかますそれがやっぱカッコいいだろ
Pushing through the fog without flattery, that's what's cool, right?
ギンギラギン
Gingiragin (Flashy and Bright)
無礼正直な言葉で ステージ上ではガスだけ
With rude and honest words, on stage it's just gas.
頭の中にこびりついて取れぬ景色見せるだけ
Just showing a view that's stuck in your head and won't leave.
この波の毛並み並みじゃないけど
The texture of these waves isn't ordinary, but...
何者より高く波に乗るな舐めないでほしいぜ
...don't ride the wave higher than anyone else, don't underestimate me.
ネットはさながら風呂場の延長
The internet is just like an extension of the bathroom.
データの洪水かつ日々炎上
A flood of data and daily controversies.
石川みたいに身を入り洗浄
Cleansing oneself thoroughly like Ishikawa.
一生戦場それがランダム
A lifelong battlefield, that's randomness.
このまま行こう
Let's keep going like this.
どんな甘いも酸いも全部食らってみせるぜ
I'll show you I can take all the ups and downs.
このまま行こう
Let's keep going like this.
どんな不意な不運に目眩っても
No matter how unexpected the misfortune or how dizzying it gets...
錆びた鎖じゃ意味はなさず
A rusted chain serves no purpose.
首元光らせギンギラギンに
Making the neck shine, flashy and bright...
ありのまま行く
...going exactly as I am.
真相俺は見せるだけ不敵な目線を得るまで
I'll just show you the truth until I get that fearless look.
金食らうほどに下品に艶を
Adding a vulgar gloss as much as money can buy.
我が身を投じる場所なら絶文
If it's a place to throw my life away, it's a masterpiece
今この場所この舞台で決定
Decided right here, on this stage
五右衛門みたいに かなかな絶景
Like Goemon, quite a view
向かい風 吹いたって
Even if a headwind blows
逆に乗りこなしてやるぜ 俺にとっちゃこれが常で
I'll tame it instead; for me, this is normal
言葉出せぬくらい 暗い時代なんて言うけど
They say it's a dark era where words can't be spoken
だけど見せてやる ぶちかましてやる
But I'll show you, I'll blow you away
俺は人生 必死で死ぬまで 死ねんガチな勢いや実践
In this life, I'm desperate until the end; I can't die with this momentum
その目開け バカでけぇことやろうぜ
Open your eyes, let's do something huge
このまま行こう
Let's keep going like this
どんな前も酸いも 全部かっ攫って見せるぜ
I'll snatch up all the highs and lows
このまま行こう
Let's keep going like this
どんな不安や不満や吸い込みに 目食らっても
Even if I'm blinded by anxiety, dissatisfaction, or intake
このまま行こう
Let's keep going like this
どうせならばやれることは 全部やっていこうぜ
If we're doing it anyway, let's do everything we can
このまま行こう
Let's keep going like this
いつか何もかも 終わってしまったとしても
Even if one day everything comes to an end
野暮な戯言にゃ 目もくれず
Without paying heed to unrefined nonsense
俺はこの人生も
I'll make this life, too
ギンギラギンに輝かせてくだけだ
Shine dazzlingly
ギンギラギンに ありのままに
Dazzlingly, just as you are
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
終わったー！
It's over!
ということで、二人目のゲスト！
So, our second guest!
自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourself!
はい、ぽぽぽ！ホロライブReGLOSS、轟はじめです！番長！よろしくお願いしまーす！
Hi po po po! Hololive ReGLOSS, Todoroki Hajime-desu! Ban-cho! Nice to meet you!
今日、今日もなんだこれ、うむうむ？
Today, today too, what is this, umu umu?
うむうむ、うむうむ。
Umu umu, umu umu.
やめて、そのノリ。もう。
Stop that. Seriously.
こっからもうこれやる、うむうむ。はい、ぽぽぽ。
From here on we're doing this, umu umu. Hi po po po.
いやー、はじめこと番長！めちゃありがとね、来てくれて。
Man, Hajime, aka Ban-cho! Thanks so much for coming.
できたよ！ できたね！
We did it! We did it, right!
できたよ！ できたよね！
We did it! We really did it!
ギンギラ、感想はどうですか？
How was 'Gingira'?
いや、難しかったー！
Man, it was hard!
あの、まだ見てない方はね、昼にね、一応、ギリギリのダンス練習やってて。
For those who haven't seen it, we had a last-minute dance rehearsal this afternoon.
うん。そこで振り作ってたんですよ。
Yeah. We were making the choreography then.
だからもうさっきの、多分、間違えたところもあったと思うので。
So just now, there were probably some mistakes.
そこ、ごめんなさい。すいませんでした、本当に。
I'm sorry about that. I'm really sorry.
まぁ、頑張りましたよね。
Well, we worked hard, didn't we?
はい！でも30分はないよ、普通。
Yes! But 30 minutes isn't enough, normally.
いや、本当に短すぎた。
No, it really was too short.
ね！でも楽しかった。
Right! But it was fun.
ね！よかった。
Yeah! I'm glad.
え、あのね、あそこの振り好きなの。
You know, I like that part of the choreography.
なーにゅなーにゅなーにゅなーにゅなーにゅ。
Nanyunanyunanyunanyunanyu.
わかる！
I know!
これがね！
This part!
わかる、わかる。めっちゃわかる。
I know, I know. I totally get it.
爆速だったけど。
It was crazy fast, though.
うん、爆速だったのこれでしょう。
Yeah, this was the crazy fast part.
うん、それも速い。
Yeah, that's fast too.
ぅ、ぅ、ぅ、ぅ！これね、めっちゃ速かったね。
Ugh, ugh, ugh, ugh! This was really fast.
でも成功したよね！
But we nailed it!
成功した！本当に嬉しい。
We did! I'm so happy.
いや、これもね、あの、みんなから、なんか番長とハコ太郎一緒に踊りたい、踊りたいって。
Well, also, everyone was saying they wanted to see Ban-cho and Hakotaro dance together.
めっちゃコメントもらったんで、これで満足してるかな？
I got so many comments like that, so I hope you're satisfied with this?
満足、満足してますか？大好きかな？
Are you satisfied? Do you love it?
滑舌取れてつつ分かんない。
I don't know if my articulation was okay.
だからまぁ、これからもね、本当に一緒に踊りたいなって。
So, well, I'd really like to dance together again from now on.
ね、いつかまた踊ろうね。
Yeah, let's dance again sometime.
ね。可愛いし。
Right. And you're cute.
ハコちゃん可愛いじゃない。
Bae-chan, you're cute too.
可愛い。何よ。
Cute. What?
え？
Eh?
何を？
What?
何よって言ったら、何よって言ったの。
I said 'What?' and you said 'What?'.
あ、何よか！
Ah, 'What?'!
「何を？」って聞こえた。「何よ？」え？
I thought I heard 'Nani o?'. 'Nani yo?' Eh?
聞き間違え！
Misheard it!
ごめん。疲れてるから！
Sorry. I'm tired!
お疲れ様だよ、もう。
You're tired, already.
うわー。でも、多分、これ僕も初めてなんですよ。
Whoa. But, probably, this is a first for me too.
ほりゃ？
Oh?
あの、他の人と振りを作ることも初めて。
Making choreography with someone else is a first too.
初めて。え、作ったことある？
A first. Eh, have you done it before?
ホロライブ入ってからない。
Not since joining Hololive.
おお。僕は人生初めて。
Oh. For me, it's a first in my life.
えー！嬉しい。
Eh! I'm happy.
他の人と作ったことない。なんか恥ずかしすぎて作れなかった、元々。
I've never made it with anyone else. I was originally too embarrassed to.
恥ずかしい？
Embarrassed?
恥ずかしい。なんか自分の、そう、自分のアイデアちょっと出しすぎかなって。
Embarrassed. Like, 'Is it too much to put my own ideas out?'
「いや、無理や、これどうかな？」みたいな。今まで無理やった。
Like 'No, that's impossible, what about this?'. It was impossible until now.
そう、そう。
Yeah, yeah.
え、でもめっちゃかっこよかったよ。
But it was really cool.
ありがとね。ハコちゃんもめっちゃかっこよかったよ。
Thank you. You were really cool too, Bae-chan.
And for the overseas people, I hope...
...we've gotten a lot of your messages about wanting to see us perform together...
...so I hope this matched, I don't know, lived up to your expectations.
Um, and if you haven't checked it out, we did do a last-minute dance rehearsal...
...making the chorus of the choreography you just saw...
...which is why we may have made a few mistakes because it was so last minute, but!
まぁ、そこはね。
Well, you know how it is.
Please just overlook that anyway.
ありがとね！
Thank you!
ありがとう！
ありがとね。
Thank you.
ベぇちゃんとして、ま今日じゃないけど、お誕生日おめでとう！
As Bae, well it's not today, but Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
素敵な１年を過ごしてね。
Have a wonderful year.
うふふ。ななななになに？
Hehehe. Wha-wha-what?
まということで、ライブも後半行ってるので、
So, we're heading into the second half of the live,
これからもまだまだね曲があるので、ぜひぜひ聴いてください。
there are still more songs coming up, so please do listen to them.
We are still, we're in like the uh later part of the live
so we still got a lot of songs for you guys to listen to so please um...
I said we, there's no one else here. Hehe.
This is me and stuff but I've got a lot of other songs for you to listen to
so please continue listening, thank you.
There's the next song.
Okay, let's go. Alright, I'm gonna get ready. Okay.
朝が来る
Lyrics, Music: 梶浦由記
Morning is Coming
Lyrics, Music: Yuki Kajiura
傷だらけの世界の端に
On the edge of this world full of wounds,
闇が重たくもたれかかる
Darkness leans heavily,
覚めない時の中
In the time that doesn't wake up,
悲しみはどこまでも追いすがって
Sadness chases everywhere,
それでも空は夜明けを探して
Even so, the sky searches for the dawn,
取りに行く未来
The future we go to take...
僕らは弱くも儚くもないよ
We are neither weak nor fleeting,
信じて愛して
Believe, love,
燃え尽きていく
and burn out...
繰り返し繰り返し 血を流す魂が
Again and again, the soul that sheds blood,
夢を見るその先に
Beyond that dream...
輝いて輝いて 新しい朝が来る
Shining, shining, a new morning comes,
希望を掲げ
Holding hope high...
君を呼んでいる黎明
The dawn is calling you...
失うことで落ちていくか
Will we fall by losing,
それとも光を追いかけるか
or will we chase the light?
選んできた道に散らした
Scattered on the path we chose,
涙も傷も遠くなって
tears and wounds are far away,
息を殺し強欲の影見上げれ
Hold your breath and look up at the shadow of greed,
それでも鮮やかに風を切って
Even so, cutting through the wind vividly,
手に入れる未来
the future we obtain...
情熱がいつだって灯火になるよ
Passion will always be a lamp,
天高く昇れと
Climb high into the sky,
狼煙を上げて
and raise a signal fire,
風になり花開き 魂を掻き鳴らす
Becoming the wind, flowers blooming, playing the soul,
僕らが急ぐ場所へ
to the place where we hurry...
華やいで華やいで 新しい朝が来る
Brilliant, brilliant, a new morning comes,
光が
The light,
たなびく方へ
towards where it drifts...
夜のもう一つ向こうまで
To one more beyond the night,
どうしても届かない
No matter what, it doesn't reach...
手のひらを支えてくれ
Support my palm,
声がいつの間にかこんなに響いてた
Before I knew it, my voice was echoing like this...
君の行く場所に光あれと祈った
I prayed for light to be in the place where you go,
全ての心のため
For all hearts,
繰り返し繰り返し 血を流す魂が
Again and again, the soul that sheds blood,
夢を見るその先に
Beyond that dream...
輝いて輝いて 新しい朝が来る
Shining, shining, a new morning comes,
もうすぐ
Very soon...
始まる
It begins...
…君を呼んでいるねえいえいえ…
...is calling out to you, yeah, yeah, yeah...
傷だらけの 世界の頭上に…
Over this scarred world...
BANG!!!
好き 嫌い 常識 I don't care I don't care
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care, I don't care
…with a bang!
...with a bang!
かかってこい Majority 私に負けはなし
Come at me, Majority, there's no losing for me
ここまでって引くんだ そのボーダー誰のルール？
Drawing a line here, whose rule is that border anyway?
あの日乗り越えた ウィンカー 強くなった…
The blinker I passed that day, I've grown stronger...
…私が笑い飛ばしてあげる ハハ！
...I'll laugh it all off for you, haha!
言いたいことは言う やりたくないことはしない
I'll say what I want, I won't do what I don't want to
悪意気にしない みんな時間の無駄だぜ
I don't care about malice, it's just a waste of everyone's time
私 私も構わない ニューノーマルの事態
Me, I don't mind either, it's a 'new normal' situation
Everybody say I want to be free
YESもNOも言わない それじゃ何も変えられねぇ
If you don't say yes or no, you won't change a thing
Everybody say I want to live more
あなた自身が肯定 生きてるんだって
Affirm your own self, that you're alive
…ねえ 生きてるんだって…
...hey, I'm telling you I'm alive...
生まれたその時から 選んできたの 思い出せ
Remember that you've been choosing since the moment you were born
私は私だ 不可能なことなど
I am who I am, things like the impossible
何一つもない そうじゃない？ 難題自分に
Don't exist at all, isn't that right? To my difficult self
好き 嫌い 常識 I don't care…
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care...
…with a bang!
...with a bang!
Again 好き 嫌い 常識 I don't care…
Again, likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care...
…with a bang!
...with a bang!
する手鳴らせ このリリックかませ
Clap your hands, let these lyrics hit
分からせ 挑発 下向いて舌打ちからの ハハ
Make 'em understand, provocations, look down, click your tongue, then haha
Excuse me 足元ズバリ 返しくらいの
Excuse me, right at your feet, like a comeback
パンチライン 聞かせてあげる
I'll let you hear the punchline
やってから考えな 私がついてるから
Think after you act, because I'm with you
Everybody say I want to be free
格伸びとか習慣 全部黙らせ
Status, customs, shut 'em all up
…目覚ませ お開…
...wake up, the end...
Wake up, wake up 生きてるんだって
Wake up, wake up, that I'm alive
ねえ 生きてるんだって
Hey, that I'm alive
生まれたその時から 選んできたの 思い出せ
Remember that you've been choosing since the moment you were born
私は私だ 不可能なことなど
I am who I am, things like the impossible
何一つもない そうじゃない？ 難題自分に
Don't exist at all, isn't that right? To my difficult self
生まれたその時から 選んできたの 思い出せ
Remember that you've been choosing since the moment you were born
あなたはあなただ 不可能なことなど
You are who you are, things like the impossible
何一つもない そうじゃない？ 難題自分に
Don't exist at all, isn't that right? To my difficult self
好き 嫌い 常識 I don't care…
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care...
…with a bang!
...with a bang!
Again 好き 嫌い 常識 I don't care…
Again, likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care...
…with a bang!
...with a bang!
Whaaa! How was that? Bang bang bang bang bang!
Oh, I feel like we did a lot of songs and I didn't really get to talk about them
because there were other guest parts in between but,
uh, there's a couple of songs that I performed that I've said that I've always wanted to sing
BANG!!! has been one of them, so I hope you enjoyed that
and then there was Asa ga Kuru with the umbrellas and, I don't know, I hope you all enjoyed
There are still some songs I want to perform but before that,
I have TWO announcements!
Not one, TWO! And here is the first one.
Ta-da!
最初は、何が…
First, what is it...
…誕生日記念グッズ2025! My birthday goods for 2025.
...Birthday celebration goods 2025! My birthday goods for 2025.
Birthday Celebration 2025!
Alright, so the Birthday merch for 2025, even though it's not really my birthday...
...um, it's looking like this!
Isn't it amazing?
Shall we have a look through them? Okay!
Can I get the first item, please?
最初の商品お願いします！
First item, please!
ドードーン！
Ta-da!
-KAGURA- Double-Layered Acrylic Block
Oh my goodness, look at that!
The first item we have is an acrylic block...
...done by the amazing Mika-mama!
Mika-mamaが書いてくれた絵ですよ！
It's art drawn by Mika-mama!
和の心じゃないですか！
Isn't it the 'Wa' (Japanese) spirit!
'Wa' is so...
...it's got the heart of...
...the Japanese, I don't really know how to say it.
But um, I've always wanted an acrylic block.
I haven't done—I haven't made one yet.
So I really hope that you display this in your homes.
みんなね、あの...
Everyone, um...
...今までアクリルブロックはやったことないんで...
...I haven't done an acrylic block before...
...ぜひ、よかったら買ってみてください。
...so please buy it if you'd like.
Um, it's me dancing in a festival.
はい、踊ってる僕なんです。
Yes, it's me dancing.
めちゃくちゃいい！
It's so good!
あと、あの、一応ダブル、ダブルDって感じ？
Also, um, it's like Double, Double D?
I think it's... I don't really know how to explain it, but...
...it's kind of like a two-layered type acrylic block.
So it kind of gives the image of it being 3D,
which makes it really cool. So if you want, please get it!
イヒヒヒヒ！って感じです。
Hehehehe! That's how it is.
あの、はい、じゃあ次の商品お願いします！
Um, yes, well then, next item, please!
ダダダダーン！
Ta-da-da-da!
The Rat Sack II Duffel bag
I'm so excited about this one.
The next item is the Rat Sack II Duffel bag!
Uh, this is—I wanted to create a dance bag,
...duffel bag, gym bag, because mine is kind of breaking...
...and I kind of need another one.
So, I reused the design that I came up with...
...from I think it was two years ago, my birthday, the very first Rat Sack...
...the crossbody bag if you guys remember. It is the same design...
...but just enlarged, and it has a lot of pockets and can fit a lot of things.
And also, it's good for gym, it's good for dance...
...it's also good for travel. It's really good carry-on luggage as well...
...'cause it's like big, it fits stuff, but not too big, you know?
Um, and there is like, you know, the transparent pocket...
...like in the original crossbody bag. You can put your pins...
...but they won't like, you know, get destroyed and you can protect them and stuff like that.
Yeah, あの、このバッグがめちゃくちゃお気に入りです。
Yeah, um, I really like this bag.
実はね、自分もねダンスバッグ欲しくて作ったんですよ。
Actually, I wanted a dance bag myself, so I made it.
で、2年前のクロスボディバッグもあったんですけど...
And, there was also the crossbody bag from 2 years ago...
...同じデザインで作ってみたんです。
...and I tried making it with the same design.
めっちゃいいでしょ！
It's great, right!
ね、ジムとか旅行とかダンスとか、全部使いやすいんで...
Right, for the gym, traveling, dance, it's all easy to use...
...ぜひ買ってください！
...so please buy it!
Uh, yeah, and then, next item!
次の商品お願いします！
Next item, please!
ウーー！
Woo!
The DripTaro Necklace
I finally did it, guys! Made the DripTaro necklace.
Yeah, I really like this kind of style of necklaces...
...and I've always wanted to make one. And now I did!
Look, there's so many little—there's so many different parts to it.
There's like the tag and the dice and the cross. It's just very Drip.
ね、かっこいいネックレス。自分もめっちゃ好みで...
Right, a cool necklace. I really like it too...
...作ってみた。ぜひ買ってみてください。
...so I made it. Please try buying it.
で、次！お願いします！
And, next! Please!
Next, we have the full set bonus!
-KAGURA- Keychain
こちらあね、It is exclusively available for those who buy the full set.
This is, um, it is exclusively available for those who buy the full set.
フルセット、ですか、貰えないやつなんで...
It's something you can only get with the full set...
...ね、you can put it onto the bag. バッグに付けられますとか...
...right, you can put it onto the bag. You can attach it to the bag...
...ね、もしよかったらお願いします。
...so if you'd like, please.
で、we still have more! 次お願いします！
And, we still have more! Next, please!
次はね、this is... そうだよね、フルセット...
Next is, this is... right, the full set...
Complete Set Purchase Bonus
...um, I'm not signing every single one this time. I'm sorry.
My arm is literally gonna fall off.
So there is a limited edition where you do get a hand-signed...
...postcard by me. Um, if you know, there is a limited number...
...so please do check it out after the live.
あの、今回はね、直筆サインは数量限定だから...
Um, this time, the hand-written autograph is in limited quantity, so...
...ライブが終わったら、あの、ぜひみんな買ってね。
...once the live is over, um, please buy it, everyone.
今回はね、全部サインできなくって本当にすみません。
I'm really sorry I couldn't sign everything this time.
もう、腕がもう終わってるんで。すみません。
My arm is already finished. I'm sorry.
はい！(笑)
Yes! (Laughs)
And I think we have one more thing, もう1個なんかありますよね。次お願いします。
And I think we have one more thing, there's one more thing, right. Next, please.
Um, this is actually very special. This hasn't happened before,
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PR card
...but if you do buy the full set, there is an extra bonus as well.
It is one card that can be used in the hololive official card game!
This is the special Oshi-holomen card, exclusively available if you buy the full set.
So if you haven't played yet, you can check out the card details, make sure you know how to play on the...
...hololive official card game homepage. So please be sure to take a look.
You get Mika-mama's amazing art on one of the cards.
But yeah, そうだよね。
But yeah, that's right.
初めてカードゲームのようなカードも、あのフルセット買ってくれる方に...
For the first time, to those who buy the full set, a card like from a card game...
...もありそうなんで、
...is likely,
ぜひみんな買ってください！はい！
so please everyone, buy it! Yes!
というわけで、That is...
So with that, that is...
...my Birthday Celebration 2025 merch! Yay!
みんなに買ってね。
Everyone, please buy them.
お願いします。
I'm counting on you.
Now, I said there were two announcements.
That was one.
I wonder what number two is.
何でしょう？
What could it be?
What is the second announcement?
Maybe I can give you a hint, but...
...first, I want you to listen to this last song!
Wild, hammy, Adam, Babel queen.
狂わす現、証言、生、狂宴。
Maddening reality, testimony, life, a feast.
狂宴 -FEAST-
Lyrics, Music, Arrangement: biz, ZERA
FEAST
Secret それは賞賛の
Secret, it's a praise,
Direct サプライズくらい
a direct surprise.
お耳はこちら手の鳴る方へ
Come this way to the ears, where the hands clap.
もう誰も止められない
No one can stop it anymore.
Don't stop, a-bangin', go go.
獰猛 騒げ 暴動
Ferocious, make some noise, riot.
その胸に牙を突き立てて
Drive your fangs into that chest.
愛、再開、鳴らせない鼓動
Love, reunion, a heartbeat that can't be silenced.
飢えた野性 叫ぶ咆哮
A starving beast, a screaming roar.
さあ解き放つ衝動
Now, release the impulse.
その鼓動が疼き出す
That heartbeat starts to ache.
騒ぐ Blood 反逆 Headshot
A noisy Blood, a rebellious Headshot.
騒々界 誠界 ばらばらに
The noisy world, the true world, falling apart.
この胸を焼き上げる 本能的感情
This chest is burning up. An instinctive emotion.
騒々界 冥界 どれあれ
The noisy world, the underworld, whatever it is.
疼く渇望 もう抑えきれない
A throbbing craving, I can't hold it back anymore.
感情を削り落とす 爽快騒鳴界
Shaving off the emotions. An exhilarating, noisy life world.
この鼓動が胸を刺すくらい
To the point where this heartbeat stabs my chest.
騒々界 誠界 ばらばらに
The noisy world, the true world, falling apart.
妄想 死の 狂宴
Delusion, death, a feast.
さあ ほら 爪を突き刺して
Come, see, dig your claws in.
さあ 狂騒に飢えて
Come, starve in the frenzy.
Don't stop 狂わせる鼓動
Don't stop, the heartbeat that drives you crazy.
症状は炎上
The symptoms are on fire.
獰猛 騒げ 暴動
Ferocious, make some noise, riot.
アバンギャルド 感情
Avant-garde emotion.
喉元に爪を突き立てて
Drive your claws into the throat.
誰にももう 止められない
No one can stop it anymore.
歪む視界 悠延性
A distorted view, relaxation,
怒り荒れ狂う感情
an anger-crazed emotion.
もう誰にも 邪魔できない
No one can interfere anymore.
Headshot!
騒々界 盛界 ばらばらに
The noisy world, the prime world, falling apart.
この胸を 掻き毟る 本能的衝動
This chest is being torn apart. An instinctive impulse.
騒々界 冥界 どれあれ
The noisy world, the underworld, whatever it is.
疼く渇望 もう抑えきれない
A throbbing craving, I can't hold it back anymore.
感情を削り落とす 爽快騒鳴界
Shaving off the emotions. An exhilarating, noisy life world.
この鼓動が胸を刺すくらい
To the point where this heartbeat stabs my chest.
騒々界 誠界 ばらばらに
The noisy world, the true world, falling apart.
妄想 死の 狂宴
Delusion, death, a feast.
むさぼり尽くせ ラブルな魂
Devour it all, the rubble soul.
踊り明かそう さあ さあ さあ
Let's dance the night away. Come on, come on, come on.
狂騒沸き上がる さあ 遊びましょう
The frenzy is boiling up. Now, let's play.
Yes she did! Yes she did! Oh!
That second announcement is a new song!
新曲出ます！
A new song is coming out!
どうだった？ How was it?
How was it? How was it?
This is what you heard...
タッタッタッタッ、狂宴！
Ta-ta-ta-ta, FEAST!
Oh my god, that's crazy.
I know, it's been a while.
I said I was going to go back to making music...
...and I kind of dabbled a little bit, you know.
Not anything too crazy, but I have a new single called FEAST, Kyoen!
It is produced by the amazing biz and ZERA-san.
bizとZERAさんの、あの、作ってくれた曲なんで、
It's a song that biz and ZERA-san made for me, so
Please have a listen! It's so vibey! It's so cool!
Um, I want to be as cool as her.
Can I be as cool as her? Is like this?
*Gurgling* No, it doesn't work. Anyway!
Um, this is my new song and um, the MV is also coming out after the live!
So please check it out. The art is done by the master Daino, as always.
Look at that! Look at that art!
あの、ライブ終わってね、MVも公開するので、ぜひ見ててください。
Um, after the live, the MV will be released, so please check it out.
今回のアートもね、ダイノ先生が描いてくださったので、本当に
The art this time was also drawn by Daino-sensei, so really
すごいMVになったと思います。And...
I think it's a great MV. And...
...um, I did the dance.
It's kind of concerning when, you know,
your original song, you feel like the dance is not as hard as other ones that I did this time, but...
Really is, really fun as well, so I'll be doing...
...I'll be uploading like shorts and stuff as well.
I wanted to, you know, embody the beast.
So please check that out as well.
And yeah, am I forgetting anything?
Oh yeah! Streaming services!
あ、配信ね、the streaming services is gonna start at midnight.
Oh, right, the streaming services will start at midnight.
Time... if you ask me timezone, I have no idea.
As... as usual, I don't have any idea about anything...
...but I'm told it is midnight at... tonight.
It'll be out, just have a listen to it when it's out.
Thank you very much.
But that's it.
Is that it? Did I do it?
How was the live? How you... how you doing?
You doing okay? Everything... everyone doing okay?
You... you doing good? Okay.
どうだった？今日のライブ、大丈夫だった？
How was it? Was today's live okay?
Did I do good?
I hope I did okay.
I still want to hear all your thoughts after the live.
I'm gonna have a, you know, long look at the hashtag #BaeDDay2025.
So... thank you so much for watching as always.
This year I really wanted to focus on dance...
...so I hope, you know, that got across.
今年はやっぱりダンス、もっと頑張りたいなと思ってるんで...
Since I've been wanting to work harder on my dancing this year...
...今日のライブでちょっとそれ、伝わってるかなって...
...I hope that came across a bit in today's live...
...伝わってるかなって、あの、ちょっと今ね...
...I'm wondering if it got through, well, right now...
...伝わったらいいなと思ってます。
...I'm just hoping that it did.
But I guess that's it! I'm gonna go die now.
Mmm, I'm so tired.
The words exiting my mouth are just gone.
I have no idea, nothing's happening up here.
But I... I will continue to work hard.
Thank you so much for a not-birthday birthday this year.
It was a little different for Baebry...
...but I guess that's the end of Baebry.
What was Baebry? Who knows.
But that's it for today! Thanks for coming!
見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to watch!
また今度ね！
See you next time!
バイバイ！バイバイ！
Bye bye! Bye bye!
KAGURA DANCE OF THE GODS 3D LIVE
CAST Hakos Baelz
THUMBNAIL Osamu Nobusawa
LOGO SpiritSnare
CHOREOGRAPHER ミュキニジマ (mjuk-nijima)
CHOREOGRAPHER mjuk-nijima
CHOREOGRAPHY SUPPORT LISA-P
DANCERS Chisato Takahashi, Minori, moe, Mishio Tokita
FILM PRODUCTION EchoMotion
MUSIC VESSEL LIFE, raihiva, SAZA, Yoshikun, Chome, Aki, um., Toshiyuki, chibi
EXECUTIVE PRODUCTION Hakos Baelz
Thank you for watching!! I SURVIVED!!
All your support means the world to me T T
ここまで本当にありがとうございます♡
Your support made this the best non-bday ever!!
これからもよろしくお願いします！
HAPPY BIRTHDAY BAE!
Thank you for watching!! I SURVIVED!!
All your support means the world to me T T
Thank you so much for everything up to now♡
Your support made this the best non-bday ever!!
I look forward to your continued support!
HAPPY BIRTHDAY BAE!
Thank you for watching
I SURVIVED!!
All your support means the world to me
そしてこれからもよろしくね♡
And please continue to support me! ♡
Your support made this the best B-day ever!!
ありがとうみんな♡♡♡
Thank you, everyone! ♡♡♡